[Music]
today we're going to talk about
jenny's jenny's darkest chocolate
specifically
now if you look in her book one of her
books jenny's splendid ice creams
it clearly shows the older version of
the recipe with cream cheese
physical chocolate coffee lots of
different things
but for some reason over time all that
stuff's been removed
and if you look on the website now on
the back of the tubs it's just cocoa
powder
i don't know why that's been removed
it's a well it's going to be down to the
cost manufacturer
all those kind of things it would just
be quite expensive to make and produce
and get out and blah blah so
they've just gone with the cocoa powder
version for retail which
kind of makes sense financially i'm not
slating
jenny's ice cream for doing this it's an
absolute normal thing to do
but is it a little bit boring just cocoa
powder i mean you can't beat a good
chocolate ice cream that's for sure
but for me i want a bit more i want a
bit more than just
cocoa powder i'm sure she uses an
excellent quality cocoa powder
i'm also going to use an excellent
quality cocoa powder
but instead of naming this one jenny's
this is what we were going to
do title of the video i've renamed this
one to
nyx mine so this is
nick's darkest chocolate ice cream
if you want to find out how to make it
stick around and we'll show you
[Music]
this is an easy one to start with so
just add your milk cream and sugar to
the pan and then gently heat
once it's warmed add in your physical
chocolate chips
once it's all melted and combined then
you need to add in your cocoa powder
coffee and salt if you have it and you
want to you can also add one teaspoon of
dutch cocoa powder but this really is
only for color
finally add in a couple of teaspoons of
skim milk powder
combine it well then turn off the heat
that mix in the fridge for a few hours
and then you're ready to churn
[Music]
i've got strong machine here so i'm
adding my chopped chocolate before the
end
but you can just fold it in after
batching it up
layer in your chocolate sauce of choice
i'm using an excellent
moaning dark chocolate sauce here but
you can make one just as easily
i'll put a recipe in the description
below should you want to do it
finally freeze your new creation for a
few hours
try not to eat it too soon
so the ice cream has been in the freezer
for four or five
six hours something like that we're
gonna take a scoop out and
see what it looks like
[Music]
and here we go scoops beautifully i mean
i can smell the chocolate coming out of
it so this is this is everything in here
this is
physical chocolate 70 cocoa solids
we've got a calabar cocoa powder which
is 24
fat we've got 100 cocoa powder dutch
process
it's just really dark actually doesn't
taste any stronger and that's a
misconception a lot of people have the
darker the chocolate the
stronger it tastes i mean it's usually
quite bitter it doesn't taste of
chocolate loses that flavor when it gets
kind of that dark
the chocolate sauce blimey there's a lot
in here
now one thing that jenny's did say in i
think one of her blog posts
was that her dark chocolate is
so close to being too much that it it's
borderline bitter it's borderline flaky
and that is kind of what you want from
something like this really intense
chocolate i mean it's one of the most
popular flavors
according to the world of the internet
and it's just nice to know that there's
you know a lot of chocoholics out there
just like me let's
dig in you've got the chunks of
chocolate going through there
it's so close to being too much
chocolate but it's
it's perfect it's it's a real
punch in the face kicking the ass amount
of chocolate in here
if you don't like chocolate ice cream
this probably isn't for you but
if you do and you like a lot of that
intense chocolate flavor
this is really something to go for you
don't have to have special chocolate
you can use whatever dark chocolate you
have available
i would say get somewhere around the 70
cocoa solids that's kind of that sweet
spot
any more than that and it gets a little
bit bitter doesn't taste like chocolate
to me
but it's surprising easy to make this
have a go
let us know what it's like send us some
pictures anyway we hope you enjoyed this
video
super dark chocolate ice cream and we
look forward to seeing you next week
thanks very much take care